### Maximo, Rafael

1437 Agrimensor Sugaya, Colonia – SP, Brazil

+55 11 98441-2010

E-mail: rafamaximum@gmail.com

37 Years old

### **Summary**

DevOps Engineer / Linux Sys Admin with more than 13 years of experience and proficiency in a wide variety of technologies. Strong knowledge in Linux(RedHat & Debian), Docker, VMware/SRM, AWS(EC2, CloudFront, Cloudwatch, IAM, Route53, S3, KMS, ECS/EC2/Fargate, DirectConnect) Knowledge in implementation of some environments with PCI standards, Automation with terraform/ansible, Firewalls (Cisco ASA, Fortinet/Fortigate Appliances, IPTables/Check Point, Load Balance A10/Kemp), with deeper experience in Data Center environments and migrating mission critical customers.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Equinix**

#### Senior DevOps Engineer 10/2018 - Current

Responsible for architect revision of cloud, hybrid-cloud and data center projects.

Implementation of terraform cloud integrated with github, slack, ansible, chef, ruby scripts and creation and customization of terraform code.

Support all aspects of the project life cycle through ITIL based Configuration, Change, Service, Incident and Problem management.

Responsible for cloud, hybrid-cloud and data center implementation and migration.

AWS network interconnection with on premise environments, migrations, RDS, EC2 instances, load balancers and autoscaling configurations. Integration of on premise environments (VMware) with multi-cloud service providers using AWS DirectConnect and Equinix Fabric.

On premise network and security configuration, routing and switching with BGP and OSPF routing, security with Fortinet Firewalls, Cisco ASA, Check Point, Web Application Firewall (WAF).

Support to project managers with customer negotiation providing technical background to guarantee project's and customer's interests.

Support to commercial teams in meetings with customers to discuss technical solutions and implementation strategies.

Support for the team's manager in facilitating some of the team's routines like daily meetings, reviews and retrospectives.

### Solutions Architect - 10/2015 - 10/2018

I was responsible for the elaboration of documents with the essential information for the activation of clients' projects. In addition, I have been working together with several teams from the initial stage of designing the project to the final stage of customer delivery, I also attend meetings with Customers, Account Managers, Project Managers and Customer Success Manager, not only to deliver the best solution and customer experience, but also to better understand their IT environment through conferences and meetings of Technical Interviews that include various scenarios and technologies, such as OS, Web Servers, Database, Network and Infrastructure on AWS and also on premises.

I transcribe documents that contain information pertinent to the products/services contracted by the client, as well as all the necessary information so that the technical team can act and carry out the provisioning of the entire environment.

### Senior Linux Systems Administrator 12/2010 – 10/2015

Analysis and implementation of projects in datacenters in São Paulo, elaboration of clients migration plans, installation and configuration of Linux servers (RHEL, CentOS and Debian) such as Web services and load balancers like Apache2, NGINX, KeepAlived, Ldirectord, Drdb, memcached, haproxy, configuration of Databases (MySQL, PostgreSQL) such as change user permissions, backup & restore of client databases, installation and configuration of the Oracle RAC infrastructure in addition to creating and configuring Firewalls of clients like policies, NAT and IPsec VPN in Fortigate/Cisco Asa/Check Point appliances or IPTABLES.

Extensive working experience in process scheduling, disk and file system I/O, kernel tuning, TCP/IP networking.

Installing Veritas Volume Manager and configuring Disk Groups, Volume Groups and Logical volumes to manage the storage resources.

Effective use of LVM disk Management tool to Create, extend the Volume Groups on RHEL/Debian systems.

Patching of RHEL/Debian/Ubuntu servers for PCI compliance

Working with Logical Volume Manager and creating of volume groups/logical performed Red Hat Linux Kernel Tuning.

## Llevon Informatica

### Linux System Admin - 08/2009 - 12/2010

Administration of Linux Firewall (Iptables) and also responsible to implement and maintain VPN such as OpenVPN, Client Site VPN and IPsec VPNs.

Handling problems or requirements as per the ticket (Request Tracker) created.

Mass Build of Linux OS servers using kickstart /jumpstart automation application.

production requirement as well as App/Dev requirement.

Installation of Oracle 11g and Apache 2.x on Linux environment.

Worked extensively with Network File System (NFS) for storage, Samba Server/keepalived.

Monitored System Activities like CPU, Memory, Disk and Swap space usage to avoid any performance issues.

Software package and patch administration, involving adding and removing software packages and updating patches.

Configuration and administration of LDAP, NFS and NIS in Linux and also implemented Samba for sharing of resources between Linux and Windows environments.

Maintained proper documentation of all the activities carried out during the project.

## **Smart Union Informartica**

### Linux System Admin - 08/2007 - 06/2009

Provide operational support for mission critical systems in a 24x7 regime (weekly rotating shifts).

Maintenance of hardware/software configurations for systems based on Red Hat Enterprise Linux or Oracle Linux distributions.

Build, implement and maintain system-level software packages which are related to block devices, clustering, file management, backup, web applications, DNS, LDAP.

Configure and troubleshoot applications whether third-party systems as well as in-house developed applications.

Develop, install and maintain utility programs/scripts to manage application start, stop, end-of-day, monitoring and failure/recovery.

Gather requirements and implement changes by following processes.

Responsible for configure and maintain environments using Samba + Lap integrated, implementation of firewall linux using iptables.

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

LPIC-1 - Linux Professional Institute (ID: LPI000223655, Verification Code: qah986yt9q)

LPIC-2 - Linux Professional Institute (ID: LPI000223655, Verification Code: p3hrg9bv83)

LPIC-3 - Linux Professional Institute (ID: LPI000223655, Verification Code: rfjqdfl5x3)

Check Point Certified Security Administrator R77 - 2e37cf46-86f9-4150-8964-5c6b8ea946a5

RHCE - RED HAT CERTIFIED ENGINEER - Ansible Version - CERTIFICATION ID: 210-042-289

AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate - Validation Number CN2EDC5BDBEE1J9Y

RHCSA - RED HAT CERTIFIED SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR - CERTIFICATION ID: 210-042-289

HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate - b175b321-f0c5-4137-b39c-d874b36fe527

NSE 4 Network Security Professional - Fortigate - Certification Number hRrCCS9rfl

EXIN Agile Scrum Foundation – Verification Code 6044762.20678657

VMware VCP 5.1 - VMware Certified Professional

**ITIL Foundation** 

### LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

English – Advanced Portuguese – Native

#### **Education**

Universidade Nove de Julho - Graduated in Computer Network